<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pages on Beyond the Buzz</title>
        <link>http://deidnani.github.io/page/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pages on Beyond the Buzz</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://deidnani.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>http://deidnani.github.io/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://deidnani.github.io/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a Master&amp;rsquo;s student in Georgia Institute of Technology studying Computational Science and Engineering &amp;amp; Quantitative and Computational Finance, and I am especially passionate about artificial intelligence and how it can revolutionize our lives. I started my journey in artificial intelligence through the several classes at Georgia Tech and I further polished the skills I learned in several of these classes through several internships in this area as well as research in the intersection of NLP and Finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, I started to get more interested in other areas of artificial intelligence as well such as reinforcement learning, computer vision, machine learning systems design, machine learning with limited supervision, etc. To foster this interest, I kept up-to-date with the latest news in AI with Youtube channels such as Yannic Kilcher and the AI Epiphany as well as blogs by the leading organizations in AI today such as OpenAI, DeepMind, Meta AI, Microsoft Research, Google Brain, Amazon Research, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I was looking for a one-stop shop where I could get detailed breakdown of research papers written by a diverse group of organizations and covering a variety of topics, so I decided to create this blog. I have often heard that &amp;ldquo;The Best Way to Learn Something is to Teach it to Someone Else&amp;rdquo; so I decided to put this principle to the test through the articles that I will publish in this blog. I hope that this blog not only helps me better understand the innovations discussed in these papers but also will help you to appreciate the many capabilities of AI (beyond it just being another &amp;ldquo;buzzword&amp;rdquo;) and how it will a major driver of the next scientific revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>http://deidnani.github.io/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://deidnani.github.io/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>http://deidnani.github.io/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://deidnani.github.io/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
